# SAMANTHA JENKINS

samanthajenkins.sj38@gmail.com 469-901-1077

# HEALTH ADMINISTRATION | BUSINESS SUPPORT

Versatile professional with over eighteen years of healthcare experience. Facilitates support services and optimising fast paced office operations. Advanced understanding of client needs with diligent attention to detail resulting in superior customer service and high levels of satisfaction. Dependable and reliable leader, capable of making a positive impact on progressive organizations poised for phenomenal growth.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Admissions/Reception; Communication; Relationship Management; Medical Terminology; Medicare/Medicaid; Outpatient Referrals; Analytical Thinking

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Microsoft Office (PowerPoint; Outlook; Word; Excel; Access, Windows 2007/2010), Type 45WPM,

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **I-Med Physicians Network**

# Medical Records Coordinator (PRN)

Dec 2017 – Present

Ensures medical records are assembled in standard order and are accurate and complete. Files paperwork and reports in patient charts, ensuring they are completed in an accurate and timely manner. **BACK UP TO MEDICAL ASSISTANT**: Verifies patient information by interviewing patient; recording medical history; confirming purpose of visit. Prepares patients for examination by performing preliminary physical tests; taking blood pressure, weight.

### **CLERICAL:**

- Transcribe patient visit from clinic notes to patient's chart.
- · Data enter and process referrals through Tracker.
- · Follow up on referrals for completion and obtaining medical records.
- · Answer calls from patients, facilities or physician's office.

### CLINICAL: SERVE AS BACK UP TO MA DURING CLINIC

- Greets in patients arriving at office or clinic.
- · Assists patients to exam room
- · Records vital statistics, pulse, blood pressure and weight
- · Interviews patient to examination rooms and prepares them for physicians
- · Removes sutures
- · Assists physicians during examination
- · Faxes prescriptions to pharmacy
- · Ensures patient rooms is stocked with necessary medical supplies
- · Prepare treatment rooms for patient examinations, keeping the rooms neat and clean
- Sanitizes treatment rooms daily

# SAMANTHA JENKINS

samanthajenkins.sj38@gmail.com | 469-901-1077

# **Palomino Place Nursing Home**

#### Dec 2016 – Present

CNA/Restorative Aide

Demonstrate interpersonal skills to bond and relate with patients on a close level to win their trust and cooperation during treatment. Communicate with staff on patient's treatment plans.

- Maintain records of patients' health condition; monitor their daily progress, landmarks and shortfalls. This is important to identify routines and techniques that are most effective to patients
- Inform nurses of developments in patients' health
- Team up with nurses in making adjustments to patient's treatment technique or in developing new treatment techniques for patients from scratch
- Aide patients' mobility by taking them from one place to another. In doing this, ensure that the environment is safe and void of anything that could cause harm to patients as they move around. The vicinity must be made safe in every possible way, including keeping sharp objects and toxic materials away from the location
- Interact closely with patients to bond with them; pay attention to their needs and body language or sign to decode what patients may be trying to say in cases where they cannot verbally express themselves due to the state of their health condition
- Ensure that patients' needs are fully met as this could affect their response to treatment and general well-being
- Responsible for coordinating care, with patients and facilities, to include faxing referrals, physician notes and scheduling of appointments.

# **Geryn Home Health**

### Nov 2007-Dec 2016

# Patient Care Coordinator

Provides coordinated care to patients by developing, monitoring and evaluating interdisciplinary care.

- Develops interdisciplinary care plan and other case management tools by participating in meetings; coordinating information and care requirements with other care providers; resolving issues that could affect smooth care progression; fostering peer support; providing education to others regarding the case management process.
- Monitors delivery of care by completing patient rounds; documenting care; identifying progress toward desired care outcomes; intervening to overcome deviations in the expected plan of care; reviewing the care plan with patients in conjunction with the direct care providers; interacting with involved departments to negotiate and expedite scheduling and completion of tests, procedures, and consults; reporting personnel and performance issues to the unit manager; maintaining ongoing communication with utilization review staff regarding variances from the care plan or transfer/discharge plan.
- Evaluates outcomes of care with the interdisciplinary team by measuring intervention effectiveness with the team; implementing team recommendations.
- Complies with hospital and legal requirements by fostering nursing practices that adhere to the hospitals and nursing division's philosophy, goals, and standards of care; requiring adherence to nurse practice act and other governing regulations.
- Protects self, co-workers, and patients by following policies and procedures to prevent the spread of blood borne and/or airborne diseases.
- Respects patients by recognizing their rights; maintaining confidentiality.
- Maintains quality service by establishing and enforcing organization standards.
- Maintains patient care database by entering new information as it becomes available; verifying findings and reports; backing up data.

**Daniel Jarvis** PhC (Patient Health Care) Supervisor **Apr 2000 – Nov 2007** 

# **SAMANTHA JENKINS**

samanthajenkins.sj38@gmail.com | 469-901-1077

Oversees licensed clinical professionals working directly with Medicare patients and ensures treatment of care is aligned with and supports the medical needs of the client. Works collaborative with all clinical staff to deliver necessary training/in-services, meet compliance requirements and provide advanced clinical home health services to those in need.

- Supervised relationships between patients and practice; liaised with patient's families and staff to discuss diagnosis, patient's condition and possible treatment options
- Completed patient admissions which include authorizing services and entering patient data (demographics, insurance, and personal health information)
- Responsible for scheduling all attendants to clients and ensuring attendants time with patients are accurate.
- Maintained office services; controlled correspondence; designed filing systems; reviewed and approved supply requisitions
- Conducted applicable dialogue with clients on services; managed a high-volume of inbound and outbound calls; conducted research, analyzed data, created reports and developed presentations

# **EDUCATION & LICENSE**

H. Grady Spruce High School – Dallas, TX. High school DiplomaDallas, TX – Certified Nursing Assistant Certificate

### REFERENCES

KEI EKEINCES		
Kenya Richardson	I-Med Physicians Network	Supervisor 469-834-6998
Ramon Parra	Palomino Place	Central Supply 214-574-8947
Tracie Neal	Palomino Place	Restorative Aide 903-204-2334